Inventory of the Klaus Kirchner collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Soviet Central Series, 1941-1945; 1-5 (Box 1-5:)
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 125, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1187)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 125... How German plutocrats are living... Germany is mourning...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: [Where is Daddy?]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 145, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1188)
    14x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [News from Foreign Countries No. 145... Enormous losses of German navy and air force...]. Photograph: German POWs playing chess. Serious battles are being fought but not on the endless snow fields but on the 64 fields of the chessboard.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 126, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1189)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 126... Berlin is laughing...]. Cartoon: Hitler shown as a henchman on a pile of skulls. [Hitler the murderer of the German people.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 146, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1190)
    14x24 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [News from Foreign Countries No. 146... Russians are fighting for peace and freedom... Bombardment of Hamburg...]. Photograph: [A German airplane shot down by Russians.]
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 21, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1191)
    14x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 21... My life is saved... Two months in Russian captivity]. Photograph: German POWs are reading the latest newspaper.
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 147, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1192)
    14x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1- 4.1942 - description: [News from Foreign Countries No. 147... America, an arsenal of freedom loving nations... Mutiny of German troops in Belgium...]. Photograph: [Meeting of German soldiers in Russian POW camp. Finally they can speak their opinion openly.]
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 156, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1193)
    15x23 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 156... Russian tanks are superior to German tanks...]. Photograph: German POWs are taking a walk after their meal.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 127, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1194)
    16x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 127... Destruction in Cologne...]. Cartoon: Göring is sitting on bags of money.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 157, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1195)
    16x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 157... The encircled German troops are doomed...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: German soldiers are surrendering holding safe conducts in their hands.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 128, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1196)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 128... The German soldier on the barbaric Hitler regime.. .]. Report on the sterilization of a man... Drawing by Erich Weinert: capitalists, SA-man, cripple meeting in a street: [There are two Germanies.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 148, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1197)
    14x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 148... Attack of the English Air Force on Germany and Italy... Heroic fight of the Norwegian people against the German invaders]. Photograph: [Russian booty.]
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 22, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1198)
    16x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 22... The new arrivals are speaking...]. Photograph: German POWs, fresh newspapers have arrived].
  - 805 kriegsgefangene deutsche Soldaten scliessen sich dem Appell der..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1204)
    21x28 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: 805 German POWs are joining the first appeal of 158 POWs demanding to fight for a free Germany. With facsimile of the appeal mentioned.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 129, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1205)
    16x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [What is happening in Germany? No. 129... Hitler is sending workers from armament factories to fight at the front...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: cripple coming home.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 158, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1206)
    17x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 158... Russians are penetrating German fortifications... A German worker is refusing to fight against Russian workers I did not want to fight. I am a worker, for what should I fight against Russian workers? ]. Photograph: [A new delivery of American tanks is reaching the Eastern front.]. The tanks shown are not of American but of Soviet production!
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 149, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1207)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1 - 4.1942 - description: [News from Foreign Countries No. 149... German-Americans against Hitler...]. Photograph: [English airmen on the Russian front.]
  - Fragen und Antworten FÜR DIE DEUTSCHEN SOLDATEN UND..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1209)
    14x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Questions and answers for German soldiers and officers. Question: What every member of the German Wehrmacht has to know...]
  - AN DIE SOLDATEN DER EINGEKESSELTEN TRUPPEN DER..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1210)
    14x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [...To the soldiers of the encircled troops of the German Army...]. Two photographs and four facsimile signatures: German communist politicians Wilhelm Florin, Wilhelm Pieck, Walter Ulbricht and Gustav Sobottka, are talking to German POWs.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 159, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1211)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 159... The snow is melting, and the German reserves are melting too...]. Photomontage: [Russian booty taken near Brijansk.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 150, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1212)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [News from Foreign Countries No.150... Spring and summer will bring Hitler his downfall...]. Caricature: [Hitler in the position of a henchman is standing on a pile of skulls.]
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor?, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1213)
    16x22 cm - 2 - paper: green or rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 130... During one night 48 houses had been destroyed... Goebbels is demanding to lie...]. Cartoon: [On the one side they live it up. The others are going hungry.]
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 23, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1214)
    17x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 23... Meeting of German officers, POWs and deputies of the German Reichstag... Wilhelm Florin, Walter Ulbricht, Gustav Sobottka]. Photograph: German POWs in the camp's kitchen.
  - LIEBE KAMERADEN an der Front, Ihr haltet uns sicher schon für tot..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1223)
    13x19 cm - 4 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Dear comrades at the front, you probably think we are dead...]. Photograph: German communist politicians Wilhelm Florin, Pieck, Walter Ulbricht and Gustav Sobottka, are talking to German POWs.
  - German soldiers listen! The famous German revolutionary poet Erich Weinert is speaking to you…, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1225-1229)
    A safe conduct in two languages with the Soviet emblem and Stalin quotes from his order No. 55 are added. Each leaflet is illustrated with different drawings and poems by Erich Weinert and others.
  - DEUTSCHE GEWERKSCHAFTLER SPRECHEN ZUM 1. MAI ZU EUCH..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1230)
    14x21 cm - 4 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [German trade unionists speak to you on the occasion of May first. Worker in soldier's uniform! Countrymen! The first of May is approaching. Since 53 years this day has been celebrated the world over...]. Facsimile signature of four prominent German communist trade unionists. Drawing by Erich Weinert.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 131, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1231)
    17x21 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 131... Hitler is the enemy of the middle classes...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: two children, nothing to eat.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 160, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1232)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1 - 4.1942 - description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 160... Defeat of the Germans at the front...]. Photograph, photomontage: Iron crosses - wooden crosses.
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 151, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1233)
    17x20 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [News from Foreign Countries No. 151... One year Soviet-Japanese non-aggression pact... Unity of the American countries in their fight against the fascist aggressors...]. Photograph: [German POWs are writing a poster for the May first holiday].
  - MAI 1942 (VON EINEM DEUTSCHEN..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1234)
    14x20 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [May 1942 (from a German soldier!) Spring! Spring!... Today is the first of May - we will surrender!...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert.
  - AM 1. MAI - KOMMT ZU UNS! Der 1. Mai..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1236)
    14x20 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [On May 1, come on over to us! May first, is the day of solidarity of people and the day of the rights of workers... May the glowing sun of May show you the way to your safety. Celebrate the day of May 1, surrender in masses and we will receive you as friends].
  - WEIGERT EUCH, IN DIE..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1237)
    14x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Refuse to join the spring-offensive German...]. Facsimile signature of four prominent German communist politicians. Drawing by Erich Weinert.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 161, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1238)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 161... The Germans are defeated at the front and behind the front...]. Photograph: [POWs are chatting with Red Army soldiers.]
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrußland leben Nt. 24, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1239)
    16x24 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 24... German POWs want a free and independent Germany...]. Photograph: Three German POWs.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 132, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1240)
    16x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 132... Anti-Hitler slogans in the streets of Berlin... Strike in an armament factory in Bremen...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: Three wounded German soldiers on a train. Caption: [Homecoming.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 152, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1241)
    18x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 152... The break-down of Hitler-Germany is near...]. Caricature: [Hitler as a Teuton]
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 162, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1243)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 162... German divisions of the "Springreserve" are being annihilated...]. Photograph: [Heavy Russian tank is ramming a German tank.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 153, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1244)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 153... Hitler's "crusade" has completely failed...]. Photograph: [English tanks at the Russian front.]
  - WILHELM PIECK DEUTSCHE SOLDATEN, LANDSLEUTE!..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1246)
    15x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Wilhelm Pieck German soldiers, Countrymen... You will die for Hitler, who is pushing Germany over the edge...]. Photograph and facsimile of his signature: Wilhelm Pieck, a German communist politician.
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 25, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1248)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 25... A day in a POW-camp... Anti-fascist marching song of POWs...]. A lecture on Heinrich Heine in a POW camp.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 163, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1249)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 163... Russian cavalry is attacking Germans in the rear of the front...]. Photograph: Russian cavalry is attacking.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 155, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1251)
    17x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 155... Hitler Germany will be hit by the force of the United Nations...]. Photograph: [English pilots in the North of the Soviet German front.]
  - Österreichische Soldaten, HITLER IST EUER FEIND! Soldaten..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1252)
    14x20 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Austrian soldiers, Hitler is your enemy! Soldiers from Austria!...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: German soldier is accusing Hitler.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 164, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1253)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 164... Russians are destructing German reserves...]. Photomontage: [One of the Russian heavy tanks in action on the Eastern front.]
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 134, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1254)
    16x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 134 ... We do not have a home anymore!...]. Cartoon: [Hitler is pushing the German people into the precipice.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. l56, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1259)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 156... The Russians will definitely defeat Hitler...]. Photograph: [German soldiers are surrendering.]
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 26, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1260)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 26... The Soviet leaflets contain the truth. The treatment and living conditions in captivity are very good and are surpassing all expectations...]. Facsimile of a letter of a German POW [Soldiers! Take care that this letter will be sent to the addressee.]
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 165, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1261)
    17x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 165... Attacks of the Red Army... Confessions of a German doctor...]. Photomontage: [German soldiers are surrendering and handing a copy of the Soviet leaflet-newspaper "Soldatenstimme" to a Red Army soldier.]
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 166, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1266)
    16x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 166... The Russians push the German invaders westward...]. Photograph: [A group of German POWs is talking to a Russian commissar.]
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 136, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1267)
    16x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 136... Hitler's government is in the hands of German plutocrats... Hitler is the enemy of German peasants...]. Drawing: [The SS-man lives it up while the people go hungry.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 157, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1268)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 152... The blow will be deadly for Hitler... English troops landed on the French coast... near Boulogne... Armed uprising against German occupants in St. Nazaire... On both sides more than 800 persons having been killed and wounded]. Photograph: [German troops surrender].
  - HITLERS NIEDERLAGE IST DEUTSCHLANDS RETTUNG..., 1942 April (Folder 2: 1269)
    15x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Hitler's defeat will be Germany's recovery... Hitler is not Germany...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: [German soldiers are reading Stalin's order...]
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 27, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1270)
    16x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 27... The Soviet Union is adhering strictly to the Hague Convention on POWs... The Russian commissar met me as a comrade]. Photograph: German POWs are listening intently to the Russian commissar.
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 158, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1271)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 158... The war will end with Hitler's defeat...]. Caricature: Goebbels is spreading printed lies but he will not be able to avoid the defeat of Hitler's army.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 137, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1272)
    17x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [What is happening in Germany? No. 137... How the Nazi-bandits cheat the German people...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: On one side they live it up, the others go hungry.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 167, 1942 April (Folder 2: 1273)
    17x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 167... The Red Army is breaking German resistance...]. Photograph: [Russian booty.]
  - Hitler hat Euch betrogen: ABLÖSUNG..., 1942 April (Folder 3: 1274)
    14x22 cm - 2 - paper: green or rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Hitler betrayed you: replacements will not arrive!... You believed, hoped and waited. Hitler betrayed you... spring is already here but replacements will not come...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: German soldiers are reading Stalin's order No. 55.
  - DEUTSCHLAND RUFT! Deutsche Soldaten!..., 1942 April (Folder 3: 1275)
    14x20 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [Germany calling! German soldiers! Hitler's war machine is running to extort from you enormous war profits... The Russians do not take prisoners. Do not believe this lie!...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: a German soldier, safe conduct in his hand, is surrendering.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 138, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1276)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 138... English bombers over Schweinfurt...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: [Again, mother brought nothing...]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 159, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1277)
    17x20 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description: [News from Foreign Countries No. 159... America is producing equipment for 3,600,000 soldiers...] Drawing by Erich Weinert: [A German soldier is surrendering.]
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 168, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1278)
    16x22 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [... News from the Front No. 168... The Red Army is attacking... The war against Russia made me ten years older...]. Drawing: Hitler on a pile of skulls. [Hitler, the murderer of the German people.]
  - Ihr habt zu viel geglaubt! HABT IHR DEN BETRUG NOCH NICHT..., 1942 April (Folder 3: 1279)
    19x24 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description: [You believed too much! Are you not fed up with this... Is that true? - or is that not true?...] Quotes from Nazi newspapers are confronted with sayings of Hitler and Goebbels at a later time.
  - Ihr habt diesen Krieg begonnen, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1280)
    14x19 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description: [...You have started this war - You must make an end to it!....We did not attack you...]. Drawing by Erich Weinert: [German POWs are surrendering and handing over their safe conduct leaflets to Red Army soldiers.]
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 169, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1281)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 169... Heavy losses for German troops... German soldiers are shirking...]. Two drawings by Erich Weinert: graves of German soldiers.
  - Was geht in Deutschland vor? Nr. 139, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1282)
    17x21 cm - 2 - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [What is happening in Germany? No. 139... Those in the rear area are making fun of soldier's wives... Soldiers wives demand the return of their husbands... Houses in the town of Lübeck destroyed...]. Drawings by Erich Weinert: [Another widow - another orphan.]
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 160, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1283)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 160... German soldiers refuse to go to the East front...]. Photograph: a group of German POWs.
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 28, 1942 April (Folder 3: 1284)
    16x21 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 28... Mail from home... Preparations for May celebrations in the Russian POW camps... Recognize the true enemy...]. Poem and facsimile letter.
  - Hitlers Politik des Völkerhasses führt Deutschland in..., 1942 April (Folder 3: 1285)
    23x17 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description: [Hitler's policy of hate is leading Germany to a catastrophe...]. Two drawings: [They fight against the foreign invaders.]
  - Wie die Kriegsgefangenen in Sowjetrussland leben Nr. 29, 1942 May (Folder 3: 1286)
    17x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [How the POWs are living in Soviet Russia No. 29... The Red Army is protecting the lives of POWs... The Soviet government is respecting international commitments... The note of peoples commissar Molotov on the bestialities of the German occupants...]. Photograph: German POWs are receiving medical help.
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 161, 1942 May (Folder 3: 1287)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: green - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 161... Mass attacks of the RAF on Germany and the North of France... Beaten by blows from the East and the West Hitler's war machine will break down... The French are helping British troops after their landing near Boulogne...]. Hitler caricature.
  - Frontnachrichten Nr. 170, 1942 May (Folder 3: 1288)
    17x21 cm - 2 - paper: red - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from the Front No. 170... The Red Army continues to attack. For what did he die?...] Photograph: Captured German tank.
  - Auslands-Nachrichten Nr. 162, 1942 May (Folder 3: 1290)
    17x23 cm - 2 - paper: rose - preservation: 1. Description of leaflet newspaper: [News from Foreign Countries No. 162... Colossal power is ready for the blow against Hitler... Bloody fights between Norwegians and the Gestapo...]. Photomontage: [British pilots working together with Soviet pilots at the East front.]. Note: There is no explanation why the British pilots in the illustrated photomontage carry rifles at the ready.